Resume

William E. Kempf

Advisory Software Engineer

19252 Roudebush Blvd. Noblesville, IN 46060 (317) 258-8225 wekempf@outlook.com

Profile

William E. Kempf is a software developer with more than 20 years of experience. He's looking for a senior development position working with modern technologies and methodologies.

Skills

• UI Development

Strong user interface development skills applied to desktop, mobile and web using numerous technologies.

• UX Design

Strong user experience design experience.

• Software Development

Proven software development skills using numerous programming languages.

• Unit Testing

Extensive experience writing and maintaining unit tests.

Technical

• Programming Languages

C#, C++, C, Ruby, Python, JavaScript, Java

- Web Technologies
 - CSS, HTML, JavaScript, ASP.NET, REST
- VCS
 - Git, TFS, SVN, CVS, ClearCase, PVCS
- Other
 - SQL, XML, XSLT, JSON

Professional Experience

RightRez, Inc.

Senior Advisory Engineer 2016-Present

Worked on the RightRez suite of products which booked, priced and sold airline tickets. Interfaced with GDS systems, wrote and maintained the web site and web services.

Vision Solutions

Advisory Software Engineer 2005-2016

Worked on the Double-Take suite of products which performed realtime data replication services. Developed user interfaces using XUL (Mozilla), MFC and WPF. Designed the frameworks used by both the XUL and WPF based products. Worked on the replication engine, written in C++. Worked on the Management Service backend, written in C# using WCF. Developed the REST APIs intended to replace the WCF interfaces. Wrote a prototype mobile interface demoed to Microsoft. Wrote and maintained unit tests. Created design documents.

First Data Resources

Senior Software Developer 1995-2005

Worked on the Fraud Detection Work Center (FDWC) product, written in C++ using MFC. Worked on the Java UI framework, creating custom UI controls. Developed a ticketing system for tracking issues using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and AJAX. Maintained a customer service web application written for First USA using Java, JSP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Lauhoff Grain Company

Technical Manager 1992-1995

In charge of all IT infrastructure. Wrote and maintained various database applications used to track inventory and business processes. Developed the EDI system used to track bills of lading.

Education

• Doane College

Crete NE

BS in Computer Science / Math

• Kenesaw Public School

Kenesaw NE

High School Diploma

Other Experience

• Boost.Threads

William Kempf was the original author of the Boost. Threads library, part of Boost. Presented Boost. Threads to the C++ Standards Committee for consideration on inclusion in the standard. Moderated some of the mailing lists and participated in most discussions.

• WPF Disciples

Participated in the mailing list discussions, mostly surrounding the Model-View-ViewModel pattern. Provided community support and guidance on WPF development.

• Onyx

Wrote the Onyx WPF M-V-VM library.

· Specifity

Wrote the Specificity .NET unit testing library.

Testify

Wrote the Testify .NET unit testing library, the successor to Specificity.

Publications

- C/C++ Users Journal The Boost. Threads Library May, 2002
- CodeProject Numerous articles

William E. Kempf – wekempf@outlook.com – (317) 825-2558